Marianne GENDRON

2200 Parker Street Detroit, Michigan $\pmb{\text{E-mail}:} \underline{\text{marianne.p.gendron@gmail.com}}$

Phone: (248) 739-5731

Creative Project Manager

Thanks to my 5 years of experience in numerous Marketing fields and my Master's degree, I confirmed my skills as a **Project Manager**. I specialized myself in the **digital marketing** 3 years ago. As I speak French and German, I will easily fit in a multicultural environment.

Experience

French Bilingual - Digital Marketing Account Manager

CDK Global - Detroit, Michigan

SEPTEMBER 2016- TODAY

In this digital advertising agency, I manage more than 30 active websites and provide digital marketing strategies to our customers: GM dealerships in Canada. I provide **analysis and recommendations** for their website advertising, **SEO**, **SEM** and **social media**.

- + I achieved 117% of my monthly goals from my first month
- + Subject Matter Expert (SME) for SEO and our new program platform called "NextGen"

Digital Project Manager

Eluère - Nantes, France

OCTOBER 2013 - MARCH 2016

I started as a freelance and ended up with a full time contract with this advertising agency. I managed more than 6 active web projects at the same time and confirmed my skills as a manager. I have always been able to resolve encountered issues and find the right balance between customer's and agency's needs. This advertising agency was offering an agile working environment providing flexible and productive work for the employees.

- + Realization of quotes, SOWs, planning, mock-ups and detailed specifications for digital projects
- + Managing the project team (to 6 persons) for website achievements
- + Realization of Social Media, SEO & SEM strategies & e-mailing campaigns

My best project with the agency? www.sepro-group.com (custom WordPress template): this website had to be reachable all around the world and available in 6 languages.

Marketing Manager

Webasto - Nantes, France

OCTOBER 2012 - OCTOBER 2013

During my one year apprenticeship at Webasto, I was responsible for the marketing tasks on the French subsidiary. On a daily basis, I was working with the marketing team in the HQ in Germany and was also creating my own content to fit to the French market. I created an e-mailing campaign and a new catalogue for parts.

Season Ticket Coordinator

Detroit Roller Derby - Detroit, Michigan

JULY 2017 - TODAY

As a player with Detroit Roller Derby, my job for the league is to manage the season pass holders. I am their main contact during the 8 month season and help them with their demands: seating, gifts, etc.

Education

Leaders in Training Certification – City University of Seattle

SEPTEMBER 2017 - TODAY

Studied: Case studies, Management, Communication, Leadership behaviors

Master's Degree – Marketing Project Management – IAE de Poitiers

SEPTEMBER 2011 - SEPTEMBER 2013

GPA: 3.24 / Studied: Marketing Project Management, market studies, communication strategy, international marketing

Bachelor's Degree – Management Science - IAE de Poitiers

SEPTEMBER 2010 - SEPTEMBER 2011

GPA: 3.28 / Studied: Marketing, communication, management, statistics and accounting

Franco-German expert certification DAAD - Ruhr Universität Bochum

SEPTEMBER 2009 - FEBRUARY 2010

Selection of 30 students, based on scholastic records

Studied: Marketing, German law class, translation, economic and social politics

1st / 2d year of Bachelor Degree Foreign Languages: English and German – UFR d'Angers

SEPTEMBER 2008 - JUNE 2010

English, German and Japanese

Studied: Translation, marketing, commercial law class and economic sciences

Skills & Certifications*

Languages

+ French: fluent

German : Full professional proficiency

Information Technology

- Microsoft Office Suite (Project, Excel, Word, etc.)
- + Project management (Trello, Jira, Freemind, etc.)
- + CRM Software (Salesforce, HubSpot)
- + Google tools (Google AdWords*, Google Analytics)
- Website development and administration (HTML5 & CSS3*, PHP*, MySQL*, JavaScript*, WordPress)
- + Adobe Suite (Photoshop, InDesign, Dreamweaver, Experience Manager)